John Leedom papers, Inclusive: 1954-1989, Bulk: 1964-1980
Baylor University, Baylor Collections of Political Materials
John Leedom papers
Inclusive: 1954-1989, Bulk: 1964-1980
Baylor University, Baylor Collections of Political Materials http://www.baylor.edu/lib/bcpm/
109
Pardue, F. Craig; Leedom, John N., 1921-2011.
3 document boxes.
The John Leedom papers contain a variety of materials relating to his roles in the Republican Party in Texas from the 1960s-1990s, as well as some personal and business documents.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
John Nesbett Leedom was born in Dallas, Texas on July 27, 1921. He attended Rice University, earned an electrical engineering degree in 1943, and served in the U.S. Navy during World War II. In the 1950’s, Leedom established Wholesale Electronic Supply, Inc., which he ran as CEO. In March 1956, John married his wife of 55 years, Betty Harvey Leedom.
In 1961, Leedom ran for and won a position in the Republican Party as Dallas County Chairman, a position he held for several years. In 1974, Leedom ran for Dallas City Council, where he served until 1980. In 1980, he successfully ran for Texas State Senate, serving on committees such as Education, Economic Development, and State Affairs, among many others. During his time in office, Leedom most famously wrote the Texas “Rainy Day Fund” law. Leedom served as a delegate for the 1976 and 1988 presidential elections, supporting Ronald Reagan and George H.W. Bush respectively. Throughout his political career, Leedom supported many Republican candidates for office at a local and national level, including Barry Goldwater, Richard Nixon, Ronald Reagan, and George H.W. Bush. He retired from the legislature in 1996 and continued work as a lobbyist and author until his death on May 31, 2011.
Craig Pardue, an alumnus of Baylor University, donated the John Leedom papers to the W. R. Poage Legislative Library in April 2022. Like John Leedom, Pardue resided in Dallas, Texas and worked in Texas politics. Pardue, a lobbyist, worked for Dallas County as an Assistant County Administrator of Governmental Affairs for thirty years. Prior to that, he worked for the Texas House of Representatives.
Scope and Content
The John Leedom papers span nearly 40 years. The earliest documents begin in 1954, and the collection ends with materials related to the campaign and election of President George H. W. Bush in 1989.
The collection is largely composed of documents dealing with the Texas Republican Party, particularly as it relates to Dallas County. The John Leedom papers hold newspaper clippings from the Dallas Morning News and the Dallas Herald, amongst many other local publications. The scrapbooks housed notes and correspondence between Leedom and his friends, constituents, and significant political figures including Barry Goldwater, Richard Nixon, Gerald Ford, Betty Ford, Ronald Reagan, Nancy Reagan, and George H.W. Bush. As local chair of the Republican Party and a Dallas City Councilor, Leedom also collected materials pertaining to the Republican Party and its operations in the City of Dallas. As Leedom was involved in Texas politics for decades, the collection covers several Republican National Conventions, presidential campaigns, and local Texas elections, including his own.
While most of the collection relates to Leedom's political career, his papers also contain personal family photos, vacation packets, notes and artwork from his children, and several documents from his wife, Betty.
Arrangement
The John Leedom papers were originally housed in 10 different scrapbooks, loosely organized by either date range or subject. The scrapbooks were disassembled for preservation purposes and organized into folders based on content. The original order has been maintained in the labeling of each folder, notated by a scrapbook number.
The collection is now arranged in three series: I. Republican Local, II. Republican National, and III. Personal. Within each of these series, the folders are arranged alphabetically by topic.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to the W. R. Poage Legislative Library in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 109. Acquired 2022-04-29
Related Resources
Related references
John Leedom Obituary. Dallas Morning News. June 5, 2011.
"Leedom, John N." Legislative Reference Library. Accessed September 29, 2022.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Goldwater, Barry M. (Barry Morris), 1909-1998.; Leedom, John.; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous),1913-1994.; Reagan, Ronald.
Subjects (Organizations)
Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ).
Places
Dallas (Tex.) -- History.; Texas -- Politics and government.
Subjects
Business enterprises -- Texas.; Business records.; Political campaigns -- Texas.; Political campaigns -- United States.; United States -- Politics and government.
Genres
Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Correspondence.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Republican Local, 1954-1989; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Good.
  Biography/Profile
  Series I. Republican Local is the largest series in the collection. It contains documents relating to the local reporting and local campaigning on various elections; including Leedom's 1980 Texas Senate campaign; City of Dallas matters for which Leedom served as a City Councilor; and Dallas County Republican Party business, for which Leedom served as a County Chairman. Overall, this series is in good condition.
  Index Terms
  Genres
  Photographic print
  - 1963 Special Election, Scrapbook 5 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1964 Goldwater Campaign, Scrapbook 5 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1976 Reagan Campaign, Scrapbook 7 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1980 Senate Campaign, Scrapbook 8, 1977-1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1980 Senate Campaign, Scrapbook 9, 1980-1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Campaign Press, Scrapbook 2, 1961-1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Campaign Photos, Scrapbook 10 (1 of 2), 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Campaign Photos, Scrapbook 10 (2 of 2), 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Campaigns and Conventions, Scrapbook 3 (1 of 2), 1963-1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Campaigns and Conventions, Scrapbook 3 (2 of 2), 1963-1980 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and Notes, Scrapbook 2 (1 of 2), 1954-1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and Notes, Scrapbook 2 (2 of 2), 1954-1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Dallas County, Scrapbook 4, 1963-1966 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Dallas County, Scrapbook 5, 1963-1989 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Republican National, 1962-1980; 2
  Series II. Republican National contains newspaper clippings, press releases, correspondence, and other materials relating to the 1964 and 1976 Republican National Conventions, Richard Nixon's 1968 Presidential Campaign, and Ronald Reagan's 1980 Presidential Campaign. The series is in good condition.
  - 1964 Convention, Scrapbook 1, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1968 Nixon Campaign, Scrapbook 2, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1976 Convention, Scrapbook 7 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1980 Reagan Campaign, Scrapbook 9 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Personal, 1963-1980; 3
  Series III. Personal contains notes, correspondence, artifacts, and business records from John Leedom, his wife Betty, and other family members. The folders are divided into family materials, business materials relating to Leedom's company Wholesale Electronics, or a combination of the two. Overall, this series is in good condition.
  Photographic print; Postcards
  - Leedom Business, Scrapbook 6, 1966-1970 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Leedom Business and Family, Scrapbook 4, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Leedom Business and Family, Scrapbook 7, 1971-1976 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Leedom Family, Scrapbook 3, 1963-1980 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Leedom Family, Scrapbook 6 (1 of 2), 1970 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Leedom Family, Scrapbook 6 (2 of 2), 1970 (Box 3, Folder 8)